What has been the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
What, about $750,000?
$8 million.
As an executive, it was extremely high.
I would say in excess of $2 million.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
I went into the construction field.
So I got houses, built houses, stuff like that.
Finance?
Commercial real estate.
Are you a business owner?
Yes.
Yeah.
How many assets under management
do you currently have right now?
It's probably close to a billion dollars worth of assets.
What's the blueprint that you would say
that is needed to become a millionaire
and really get serious about becoming financially free?
That's a fantastic question.
We just landed in Miami, Florida, and
we're going all around the fashion district
asking multimillionaires and luxury
shoppers how they became successful.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
So I'm a surgeon.
I went into healthcare.
I was very close with my grandmother,
my paternal grandmother, who's from Valencia, Spain.
And I went to see a hand surgeon.
I went to see a surgeon with
her when I was eight years old.
So that was a turning point for me.
And I'm a hand surgeon.
What has been the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
Oh, gosh.
I mean, all told, you know, I've
owned surgery centers and things like that.
So I would say in excess of two million.
That's incredible.
It is incredible.
But not because I'm getting paid
that way to do my surgeries,
because I was smart enough to say I'm going to
own part of the place I do the surgery center.
And now I have a network of orthopedic walk-in centers.
So that was a business I was alluding to.
And that's called OrthoNow.
How are you?
How are you able to go
from making six to seven figures?
That's actually easy.
It's working for myself.
You know, the problem is whether it be health
care or if you're an attorney or an accountant,
you're never going to do that
if you're working for a big firm.
They're making money off you, right?
Which is fine.
And some people may want that.
They don't want the headaches, right?
The business headaches, which I've had.
But I learned early on that I've got to work.
I've got to be in my own practice.
I've got to own all the components of it.
Own the real estate.
Very important also, right?
Try not to rent.
Try not to lease.
Try to own.
Own the real estate.
Because that, in and of itself, now I'm
actually selling my surgery center real estate now.
I bought it 15 years ago.
I built it out.
And now I'm selling it.
So now I'm at the point in my
life where, you know, I'm traveling a lot.
My kids are getting older.
And we're going to enjoy the fruits of that labor.
To be able to make seven
figures in today's world, that's not easy.
What has been the best financial advice
that you ever received throughout your lifetime?
The power of compounding interest.
So early on, you make sure that you invest
and you allow the money to work for you.
And one thing I'm trying to teach
my son in a place like this,
these things are nice, but, you know, I've always been
very good about not spending an excessive amount of money
when I can buy something comparable for much less.
I mean, at some point, you can splurge, right?
But when you're younger, you know,
be very judicious with your money.
Thank you so much for your time, sir.
I really appreciate you taking the time.
Thank you, guys.
You see, he all the time
sends me the videos, your interviews.
You are the best.
We love you from Argentina.
Thank you so much for your time, sir.
Thank you, sir.
Man, that was a super cool interaction.
That was a fan from Argentina.
Thank you.
with it. For someone who may be struggling
to find that winning product in their company,
what advice would you tell them? Like how did
you go about finding that winning product? I got lucky.
I'd like to tell you that I was brilliant and
I went out and sought it and researched it. I went
to a seminar, there was a product, there was a
need in the market and nobody was doing it and
so I thought you know what I'll take a chance.
My son always tells me he said dad you swing big
and I always say you're never going to hit a
home run unless you take about nine swings to get there
so that's it. What is the best financial
advice that you ever received throughout your lifetime?
Finance isn't about math, it's about choices.
It's needs versus wants. We all want everything
but what do we need? Deal with that first and
then start working on your wants and what you can
actually get from your wants while looking towards
the future. It's choices, it's not math. You crushed
that man, thank you so much for your time. Why are
you so deep? How am I going to follow that up?
How do I follow that up? Trust me, this guy,
trust me, this guy, this guy's brilliant. I believe it.
Bro, I beg nails for a living, put
that on there. I beg nails for a living.
So you
got to get that up there.
You beg nails for a living.
I beg nails for a living. I'm
a contractor and I do my thing.
You're a contractor?
Yeah.
And how long have you been in this industry for?
Goodness, I've been in it for 27 years right now.
I started as a little boy with my dad doing,
you know, small renovations, stuff like that.
What's been your secret to sales throughout your
career? How have you been able to consistently
land big deals with big clients?
Always land, always produce a perfect product. If
you do great work, they'll find you. It's
that simple.
What has been the most amount of money
that you ever made in a single year?
I can't say that in front of all
these people but let's just say I do a
lot. What would you say is the best
financial advice that you ever received throughout your
lifetime?
Look, you got to spend money to make money.
It's that simple. You can't worry about spending a
couple bucks because in order to advance, in
order to get bigger, in order to create,
you need to spend money. It's that simple, right?
Do you mean like invest back into the business?
Absolutely. You need, you know, top of the
line tools. You need top of the line labor.
The labor force is very important. You need
good guys on your team. You'll grow that way.
For sure.
You got to spend money to make money.
And the best advice, I mean, I wish I
knew 20 years ago was hustle hard
at the beginning. Hustle hard. Work on yourself,
work hard, work long hours, do your thing,
get into a gym, get your stuff together,
get your shit together and
then sooner or later it'll show.
Come on, man. You guys are awesome, man. Thank
you guys so much for your time. I appreciate that.
You want to be successful, you got to find a
good woman. I'll tell you right, put this on camera.
No, no, no.
Come here. Come here.
She's getting ready.
If you want to be successful.
Oh, no, I'll kill myself. That's okay.
You got to find yourself
a good woman. It's that simple.
We were in the same.
Because they can make or break you. I'll tell
you right now, my wealth has doubled because of this
one.
Oh, no. What about me?
No, you spend my money.
You don't help me make it.
I got you guys. That was a pretty cool snag.
One of them was an army vet and he eventually
invented a company called Cool Earth where he made
$700,000 in one year. The other guy was a
contractor in the private sector and made hundreds
of thousands of dollars in that industry. They
both delivered some great value and
some game. What'd you think about them?
One thing I got from them is just if
you do something that you love, you'll never have to
work a day in your life. And seeing that those
guys love what they do and have both are really
fulfilled in their careers. And that's just at the
end of the day, what we all want, man. Just
be happy with what we do every day and
be able to make a living and get fucking rich.
Time to go get the next one. Let's get it.
What industry did you decide to pursue a career in?
Finance.
And what are you doing exactly?
Mortgage, personal loans, credit cards. We lend out money.
Are you a business owner?
Yes.
And how long ago did you start your business?
About 20 years.
I guess. What was the turning point like in
your life that told you that you wanted to
become an entrepreneur? Did you always know
that you wanted to start your own business?
Yes.
Yeah?
100%. I always wanted to be my
own boss. Don't want to work for nobody.
Right.
What has been the most
amount of money that you
ever made in a single year?
A single year? About $8 million.
$8 million. For someone who's making six figures, right?
And they really want to try to get to seven
figures. What's the biggest mindset change or
what's the biggest thing they need to implement
to their skill set and what they're doing?
Always work your butt off and learn
how to delegate. To be an entrepreneur,
you have to trust other people to do the job for
you too. Because you know, a lot of people like to,
I can do it myself because they think that
they're going to get more done by doing it themselves
because they're afraid that somebody else is going to not
do the same work as them. You got to learn
how to trust people and delegate your risk.
Yeah.
You're responsible to other people and that's how
you're going to grow a business to like 500,
600, 10,000 employees.
Right. If you work in finance, so you
probably oversee a lot of different industries and have
a good mind for investing. Where do you
think people should really be looking to put their
money to try and multiply and
grow their income in today's world?
I mean, I'm going to say this, not a
lot of people are going to believe it. Crypto,
like the cryptocurrency, invest in that
right now. That's the new future.
Yeah. And for people that may not
believe in blockchain or even understand it,
like what would you tell them?
What would your message be for them?
We control it. Human like us control it. Money,
banks control your money when it's in the bank.
Just say, for example, you have more than
$150,000 in your bank. If banks do bad,
even if you had a million dollars in
that account, you only insured up to $150,000.
So if they lost that other money, because
you know they pay stocks, all your money's gone.
Crypto is your own shit. You can't get
it garnished. The government can't come after it.
They can't take it from you. It's always yours.
For people that may struggle with sales in
today's world, what's been your secret to sales
as a business owner? How have you been
able to consistently land clients throughout your career?
When it comes to sales, there's always something
to sell. That world right there, that job right
there will never be out of business. Sales to
me is the number one job in the world,
because there's always something to sell. A doctor sells
you. An attorney sells you. You go to a
dentist, they can tell you to do other stuff.
That's a sale. Everything in life is a sale.
And for maybe people that struggle with sales
though, what would you tell them? How can someone
get better at closing? They just got to trust themselves,
do you know what I mean? And learn from the
best. When you go into a company, ask the question,
who's the top producer here? That's the
guy you want to sit next to.
Thank you so much for your time, bro.
You got great advice, man. Really appreciate you, man.
My man made $8 million in a single
year. He came and dropped some serious gems,
some real value for all the young entrepreneurs
out there. Let's go get this next one.
All right, you guys, we'll be back to the
interviews in just a second, but I wanted to
talk about how as entrepreneurs, it's very common for us
to always be on the go and be busy day in
and day out. When we're out hustling and trying
to close some deals and really build our businesses,
it's really hard to fit in excess trips like going
to the grocery store, then having to bring it all
back to prep, cook, and clean it all up.
That entire process can take hours, which could all
be spent going back into the business. That's why
I found that the most efficient solution and my go
to has been ordering from Factor Meals. They have an
Efficient Solution. They have an Efficient Solution.
They have an Efficient Solution. They have an
incredible variety of high quality fresh meals
that are packed with amazing nutritious value and
lots of protein. In our interviews, the
most successful people emphasize that a healthy body
keeps a healthy mind. Having strong physical and
mental health really does correlate to success in
the financial world. So it's critically important to making
a healthy diet to fill your body so that
way you can stay sharp throughout the entire day.
Factor offers so many options that make it easy
to stick to my routine so I can crush my
fitness goals. Whether it's a smoothie if I need a quick
snack or a protein packed bowl with
steak, chicken, or salmon after a great workout.
Factor's always got me covered. This has been a
game changer for my routine. So head over to
Factor75.com or click the link below and use code
HardKnox50 to get 50% off your first Factor box.
Again, head to Factor75.com or click the link
below and use code HardKnox50 for 50% off your
first Factor box. What industry did you
decide to pursue a career in? Hospitality, wines,
and spirits. Are you a business owner? Yes.
How long have you been a business owner for?
It took me 20 years to get in into the shoes
that I'm in today. And now that I'm, you know, a part
partner or have minority stake in this brand, I'm
actually back to where I was before when I started
20 years ago, which is selling account by account,
bottle by bottle. Believe it or not, when you're
a business owner, the real work begins where
others end. It doesn't end at the sale. It's
what you do. And if you're a small business, you
have to roll up your sleeves and actually put in
that actual work. It's not for everyone.
Not everyone's built for that. But having worked
and experienced with many brands that are actually
being featured here today, I worked for Louis
Vuitton for a long time and some other
wonderful French conglomerates. I've been able to work with
a lot of brands that are actually being featured
here today. I've worked for Louis Vuitton for a long
time and some other wonderful French conglomerates. I've been
able to work with a lot of brands that are
being featured here today. I've been able to represent
a brand of my own and be able to
actually fulfill a dream in that in that fashion and
work hard for it as a dream come true. And
that's why I'm here today selling upstairs. What
has been the most amount of money that
you ever made in a single year? I can't put that
on tape right now, but it was a good amount. Let
you say that. Yeah. As a as an executive,
it was it was extremely high. That was pre-COVID. But
yeah, I got to enjoy a lot. But listen, it's
about you got to look at packages. You have to
look at what looks good on paper
for your resume. If you're building your career,
what features and benefits and opportunities
for growth you have within that organization,
if there's opportunity for equity, buying shares, etc.
And most importantly, you've got to get an
awesome boss. You have to look at their credentials
just as much as they scrutinize yours. And I
happen to work with some industry titans that
were multi multi multi billionaires. I worked for seven.
And so that experience that I gained from
working for these individuals, I could never replicate
in a lifetime. I was very fortunate on the
steps of my career. You've got some great advice.
I appreciate you. The channel is called the
School of Hard Knocks. All right, you guys,
we got a very special surprise for you.
We're going to be leaving the luxury shopping district
for just a slight second to go interview
Todd Napola. He manages over a billion dollars worth
of property and is the founder of one
of the largest commercial real estate companies in all
of South Florida. We're going to ask him what
it takes to become a millionaire in today's world.
Let's see what he has to say. What industry
did you decide to pursue a career in commercial real
estate? And how long have you been in
the business for 25 years? What was your first
job when you came out of school? My first job
out of college was I got into investment broker sales,
stock broker selling stocks. So you started in
finance? Yep. What was the turning point in your
life that made you decide to go into
real estate? Financial independence. How many assets under
management do you currently have right now? It's
probably close to a billion dollars worth of
assets we have in the management between stuff I
own and stuff my clients own. It's a massive
number, but the beauty with real estate is you
don't value it every day because it's not like
stocks that every day you could put on your
E-Trade account and see how much money is there.
Real estate goes up and down. And if you're
not worried about the fluctuation in prices day by day,
you're going to do just fine. But you've got to
have patience. What's the greatest lesson that
you've learned throughout your career in real
estate so far? Patience is everything in real
estate because the richest families in the world
in real estate, we all say they're generational
of course, because they started buying real estate a
hundred years ago, but you got to be the one
to start now. So I started 25 years ago, but
imagine what it'll be in a hundred years.
I won't be here. So imagine what it'll be.
When it comes to the way that people look
at money, what would you say is the biggest
difference that separates the middle class from
the wealthy? Unfortunately, a lot of people in
the middle class got stuck there. And in
America today, it's my opinion that you're almost
better off being really poor than middle class,
because there's a lot of benefits for the poor
and the rich have all the privilege. The middle
class kind of gets stuck there where they're not
getting the free college for their kids or
the free tuition, and they're not getting financial
aid. And it's hard for them, but they kind of
got stuck there because a lot of them were taught
when you're very young, that, you know, listen, you're
young, you go to school, you get a good job,
you know, you save money, you buy a house, you
pay the house off and then you retire with the pension.
And that just didn't happen. And I think
your generations figured that out, but my generation
was sold a different story and my parents
generation for sure. So the middle class kind
of got stuck into that belief. And now a
lot of them are in their sixties and seventies,
and they're sitting there with no money,
no resources, a social security, which is anemic.
And they're saying, oh my God, what did I do?
So it's upon the young generation now to see this
and know that's not going to work. So what
used to work a hundred years ago, doesn't work today.
You need to take responsibility for yourself.
What's the blueprint that you would say that
is needed to become a millionaire and
really get serious about becoming financially free?
I would be working very hard to see how I
could add value to other people. And what I always say
is find very wealthy people. So find the
wealthiest people you could be around. And for example,
I just told one of my mentor kids, I mentor,
and I said, he was a great salesperson, but he thought
he was different than rich people. And I told him to
get a job as a valet Parker at a country club
where he's parking fancy cars. And three months
later, he realizes these rich people are no
different. They tell the same jokes. They wear the
same things like you're no different. So first you
got to believe, then figure out where you could add
value. And yeah, you're going to get a lot of
money. You're going to work a lot harder than the
kid who has a lot of privilege, but it's possible.
It's very possible. And then look for people
who made it from the absolute bottom like you.
And there's a lot of them who didn't get
lucky and didn't crack the internet code. Look for people
who have done it and model those people.
Thank you guys so much for tuning in and
watching today's video. Be sure to leave a
like and subscribe for some amazing content coming soon
and click here to watch our
full interview with Miami billionaire, Grant Cardone.